Hi this is Aaron at Fitness for Life in Wilmington, North Carolina here to help give you a little guidance on how fast to walk on a treadmill.
Number 1, if we feel like it's too much then it probably is.
You have got to know your body.
We remind a lot of people here, even in our gym, don't over push yourself, you are going to end up over training, at the very worst you will create an injury so if you are on a treadmill and you kind of feel like you are pushing the limits a little too much, most likely you are.
Back off into a level that you feel a little more comfortable with because this and I can't give a number because that number is going to vary for all different types of people.
Know your limits.
Challenge yourself.
Keep a track of what your paces have been.
If you are walking at 3.2 miles an hour but you can't really do 3.5 track that.
If you continue to walk at that 3.2 level it won't take too long before you can get up to that 3.5 level.
Be endurant but continue mixing up your walking schedule.
If you have got a goal and you want to get up to a higher walking pace push yourself, come back and recover a little bit, try to get up to that mark, the closer you work towards it the more you will be able to get there but overall if you don't know how fast to walk and you feel like you are walking too fast or you are a little cautious there is probably good reason.
Be safe, walk inside your comfort zone but push the limits when you can and that's the word from Fitness for Life.